<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>IF Answers - Recent questions and answers in Meta</title>
<link>http://ifanswers.com/qa/meta</link>
<description>Powered by Question2Answer</description>
<item>
<title>Answered: Can we know a little more about the story of the Quest system? [Quest]</title>
<link>http://ifanswers.com/1044/can-we-know-little-more-about-the-story-the-quest-system-quest?show=1047#a1047</link>
<description>&lt;p&gt;I wrote a few blog posts a couple of years ago talking about the history of Quest from the beginning: &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;http://blog.textadventures.co.uk/2013/11/07/quest-is-15/&quot;&gt;part 1&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;http://blog.textadventures.co.uk/2013/11/26/15-years-of-quest-part-2-1999-2000/&quot;&gt;part 2&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;http://blog.textadventures.co.uk/2013/11/27/15-years-of-quest-part-3-2000-2004-experimenting-with-multi-player/&quot;&gt;part 3&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the rest of the story, your best bet is probably browsing the rest of the &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;http://blog.textadventures.co.uk/category/quest/&quot;&gt;Quest category&lt;/a&gt; on the textadventures.co.uk blog which has announcements on it going back to 2006.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can also fill in any gaps if you drop me an email!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<category>Meta</category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ifanswers.com/1044/can-we-know-little-more-about-the-story-the-quest-system-quest?show=1047#a1047</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2015 14:35:11 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Is there a way to edit tags in questions other than your own?</title>
<link>http://ifanswers.com/685/is-there-a-way-to-edit-tags-in-questions-other-than-your-own</link>
<description>&lt;p&gt;A lot of people seem to forget to add a tag for the authoring system they're using. With enough reputation points you can edit the question text, but it seems that you can't add or edit tags. Is it possible and if not could the feature be added?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<category>Meta</category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ifanswers.com/685/is-there-a-way-to-edit-tags-in-questions-other-than-your-own</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2015 09:16:54 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Can we add explanations to individual tags?</title>
<link>http://ifanswers.com/470/can-we-add-explanations-to-individual-tags</link>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Problem: I see questions here tagged with &quot;Squiffy&quot;, but I don't even know what &quot;squiffy&quot; is. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is there some way to add an explanation to the tags? I would like it if I could hover over tags like on stackoverflow, but if there's no support for that then maybe we should just start adding questions like &quot;What is xxx?&quot; or &quot;Explain the tag xxx&quot;?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<category>Meta</category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ifanswers.com/470/can-we-add-explanations-to-individual-tags</guid>
<pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2015 04:29:58 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Answered: On IF Answers, should comments be hidden after edits are made to a question or answer?</title>
<link>http://ifanswers.com/403/answers-should-comments-hidden-after-edits-question-answer?show=404#a404</link>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Yes, comments should be hidden if they are no longer relevant or useful.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<category>Meta</category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ifanswers.com/403/answers-should-comments-hidden-after-edits-question-answer?show=404#a404</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2015 21:36:32 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Answered: Should I use the forums to alert people to a bug I noticed?</title>
<link>http://ifanswers.com/301/should-i-use-the-forums-to-alert-people-to-a-bug-i-noticed?show=321#a321</link>
<description>&lt;p&gt;I doubt anyone would expect you to share this kind of bug on a forum, unless you were looking for feedback or a workaround, but that doesn't necessarily mean people would object if you did. I'd suggest asking a moderator at whatever forum you're thinking of.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<category>Meta</category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ifanswers.com/301/should-i-use-the-forums-to-alert-people-to-a-bug-i-noticed?show=321#a321</guid>
<pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2015 21:39:25 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Answered: What is the tag for textadventures.co.uk?</title>
<link>http://ifanswers.com/309/what-is-the-tag-for-textadventures-co-uk?show=310#a310</link>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Use the &lt;code&gt;quest&lt;/code&gt; tag, as that's what the online editor at textadventures.co.uk is - it's the web version of Quest.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<category>Meta</category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ifanswers.com/309/what-is-the-tag-for-textadventures-co-uk?show=310#a310</guid>
<pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2015 16:05:19 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Answered: Site updates</title>
<link>http://ifanswers.com/288/site-updates?show=289#a289</link>
<description>&lt;h3&gt;Mar 29, 2015&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Added the Markdown editor plugin, enabled the support for highlight.js&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<category>Meta</category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ifanswers.com/288/site-updates?show=289#a289</guid>
<pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2015 00:22:10 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Answered: How do I use code formatting in posts on IF Answers?</title>
<link>http://ifanswers.com/197/how-do-i-use-code-formatting-in-posts-on-if-answers?show=279#a279</link>
<description>&lt;p&gt;They've changed the editor, so you can now use the { } button for code. The code indentation seems to be preserved best if I first paste in the code, then highlight it and press the { } button, rather than starting with the { } button and then pasting in the code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trying to use bullets in the same post seems to throw off the code formatting, though. I haven't been able to figure out a way to make both bullets and code display correctly in the same post.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<category>Meta</category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ifanswers.com/197/how-do-i-use-code-formatting-in-posts-on-if-answers?show=279#a279</guid>
<pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2015 18:51:43 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Answered: On IF Answers, should the question itself mention the development system?</title>
<link>http://ifanswers.com/266/answers-should-question-itself-mention-development-system?show=272#a272</link>
<description>I'm not sure about this. From my experience on Stack Exchange there are times when it helps and times when it's not needed. I'd suggest we wait and see how things go for a month or so before formalising a policy.</description>
<category>Meta</category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ifanswers.com/266/answers-should-question-itself-mention-development-system?show=272#a272</guid>
<pubDate>Sat, 28 Mar 2015 21:34:24 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Answered: A lock icon appears to the left of some questions - what does it mean?</title>
<link>http://ifanswers.com/185/lock-icon-appears-to-the-left-some-questions-what-does-it-mean?show=188#a188</link>
<description>This means that the question is closed and new answers cannot be added to it. Closed questions can be edited and then hopefully brought into a better state and reopened.</description>
<category>Meta</category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ifanswers.com/185/lock-icon-appears-to-the-left-some-questions-what-does-it-mean?show=188#a188</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2015 10:01:48 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Answered: Is &quot;plot-explanation&quot; the right tag? What have you learned about the plot of Terminator that you didn't know before from reading this question?</title>
<link>http://ifanswers.com/180/explanation-right-learned-terminator-before-reading-question?show=187#a187</link>
<description>&lt;p&gt;I think it's an appropriate tag. At the moment you won't learn anything, but if someone gives you a good definitive answer then of course you will. &quot;&lt;span style=&quot;color:rgb(52, 73, 94); font-family:ubuntu,helvetica,arial,freesans,sans-serif; font-size:16px&quot;&gt;Is it possible that the protagonist is alone and only imagines crewmates?&quot; Whether the answer is Yes or No, you've learned something about the game, right?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<category>Meta</category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ifanswers.com/180/explanation-right-learned-terminator-before-reading-question?show=187#a187</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2015 10:00:12 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Answered: Can I accept more than one answer?</title>
<link>http://ifanswers.com/175/can-i-accept-more-than-one-answer?show=181#a181</link>
<description>No. You can only mark one answer as the accepted answer.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
If no answers fully answer the question, don't mark any answer as accepted.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
If the question is fully answered by a combination of answers, either edit an answer or post a new one. The idea is that people shouldn't have to scroll through multiple answers to get the solution they need.</description>
<category>Meta</category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ifanswers.com/175/can-i-accept-more-than-one-answer?show=181#a181</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2015 09:24:40 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Answered: Is this site accessible for vision impaired users?</title>
<link>http://ifanswers.com/174/is-this-site-accessible-for-vision-impaired-users?show=178#a178</link>
<description>If you confirm your email address you will not see a CAPTCHA again.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
We're using reCAPTCHA which is accessible in its new incarnation as a simple checkbox, according to &lt;a href=&quot;http://simplyaccessible.com/article/googles-no-captcha/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;http://simplyaccessible.com/article/googles-no-captcha/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
If for any reason you can't use it, you can contact a site admin - email me at alex@textadventures.co.uk &amp;nbsp;and ask me to mark your account email address as confirmed.</description>
<category>Meta</category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ifanswers.com/174/is-this-site-accessible-for-vision-impaired-users?show=178#a178</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2015 09:18:33 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Answered: I got an answer in my email but when I go to ifanswers I cant accept it?</title>
<link>http://ifanswers.com/172/got-an-answer-in-my-email-but-when-to-ifanswers-cant-accept-it?show=173#a173</link>
<description>You need to login to ifanswers before you can make changes like accepting an answer.</description>
<category>Meta</category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ifanswers.com/172/got-an-answer-in-my-email-but-when-to-ifanswers-cant-accept-it?show=173#a173</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2015 09:07:31 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Answered: What are reputation points?</title>
<link>http://ifanswers.com/166/what-are-reputation-points?show=168#a168</link>
<description>&lt;h1&gt;What are reputation points?&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Reputation points give a rough representation of how trusted a user is on this site. This site has&amp;nbsp;&lt;em&gt;community moderation&lt;/em&gt;: rather than moderators having to keep the site clean by themselves, each user is given the ability to do their part. Reputation points are used to measure how experienced you are with our Q&amp;amp;A conventions, and determine the actions you can take. There is little to distinguish between those with a high reputation and the official moderators.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;How do I earn points?&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;The main purpose of this site is asking and answering questions, so points are earned primarily through those actions. Specifically, you earn points in these ways:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;5 points per up vote on questions you asked&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;10 points per up vote on answers you posted&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;15 points if one of your answers is selected&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;2 points for selecting an answer on your questions&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;You lose points in these ways:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;-2 points if one of your questions or answers is down voted&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;-1 point when you down vote someone else's answer&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Note that you do not lose points for voting down questions. The major reason for down voting questions is if the question is a poor fit for this site. (Explanation to come later.) This is a very important process so there is no penalty for doing so. Answers are different, and so to prevent new users from feeling picked on, there is a small penalty for down voting answers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;What actions do reputation points allow?&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Once you reach these levels of reputation, you will be able to perform these actions:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;0 points: Ask and answer questions&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;15 points: Vote up&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: line-through;&quot;&gt;20 points&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;0 points for the moment: Add comments&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;50 points: Vote down&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;100 points: Edit other people's posts&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;It may seem strange that some of these actions are restricted because they seem very basic. But the core purpose of this site is Q&amp;amp;A, not to discuss or debate topics. It often takes new users a little bit of time to understand this, so we restrict some of what they can do until they've had some experience on the site. You should vote on answers according to how well they answer the specific question they were posted on, not whether you agree with them in general.&amp;nbsp;The purpose of comments is to clarify questions or to suggest improvements to answers, not argue about the content. So we restrict these things a little so that new users will become familiar with the purpose of the site first.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Note that some of these numbers will be raised once the site is a little more established and we have more high reputation users.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<category>Meta</category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ifanswers.com/166/what-are-reputation-points?show=168#a168</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2015 06:52:20 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Answered: Are new users unable to upvote/downvote responses?</title>
<link>http://ifanswers.com/159/are-new-users-unable-to-upvote-downvote-responses?show=167#a167</link>
<description>&lt;p&gt;I have just written a new&amp;nbsp;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;http://ifanswers.com/166/what-are-reputation-points&quot;&gt;FAQ page about reputation points&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You need 15 points to vote up and 50 points to vote down.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I think it would be better if the buttons weren't shown to those who can't use them. I will investigate other themes...&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<category>Meta</category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ifanswers.com/159/are-new-users-unable-to-upvote-downvote-responses?show=167#a167</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2015 06:23:41 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Answered: I got an answer! There is a big tick next to it - what does it do?</title>
<link>http://ifanswers.com/127/i-got-an-answer-there-is-a-big-tick-next-to-it-what-does-it-do?show=157#a157</link>
<description>Clicking the big check mark to the left of the answer will select it as the best answer to your question. If you do that, you get 2 points for choosing a best answer, and the person who answered will get 15 points for having their answer chosen. I'm not sure what else happens. Maybe it affects the order in which answers appear?</description>
<category>Meta</category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ifanswers.com/127/i-got-an-answer-there-is-a-big-tick-next-to-it-what-does-it-do?show=157#a157</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2015 00:39:27 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Answered: I don't get emails / How can I find emails from ifanswers?</title>
<link>http://ifanswers.com/130/i-dont-get-emails-how-can-i-find-emails-from-ifanswers?show=131#a131</link>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Check your spam folder. You may need to find the &lt;strong&gt;email address confirmation&lt;/strong&gt; email from ifanswers and click the supplied link before you will receive more emails.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<category>Meta</category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ifanswers.com/130/i-dont-get-emails-how-can-i-find-emails-from-ifanswers?show=131#a131</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2015 15:38:53 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Answered: How can I find out in ifanswers if my question is answered?</title>
<link>http://ifanswers.com/123/how-can-i-find-out-in-ifanswers-if-my-question-is-answered?show=124#a124</link>
<description>When you ask a question you can select a checkbox to receive an email notification when there is an answer. The checkbox is enabled by default.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
To find out if there are new answers, check your email. If you just made an account you will need to open your email and find the email address confirmation message which has a link to click.</description>
<category>Meta</category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ifanswers.com/123/how-can-i-find-out-in-ifanswers-if-my-question-is-answered?show=124#a124</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2015 13:38:02 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Is &quot;ratings-recommendations-reviews&quot; too long for a tag?</title>
<link>http://ifanswers.com/117/is-ratings-recommendations-reviews-too-long-for-a-tag</link>
<description>dannii: I'm unable to reply to your comment.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The reply is: I no longer desire to write tags.</description>
<category>Meta</category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ifanswers.com/117/is-ratings-recommendations-reviews-too-long-for-a-tag</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2015 13:27:30 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Answered: Do questions on a development tool need to mention the version?</title>
<link>http://ifanswers.com/12/do-questions-on-development-tool-need-to-mention-the-version?show=15#a15</link>
<description>I say let's follow the approach used by Stack Overflow, where generally questions don't have version-specific tags unless the question is specific to a particular version. For example, there are version-specific Python tags &amp;quot;python-3.3&amp;quot; etc, but most questions should use the generic &amp;quot;python&amp;quot; tag.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
However in the case of Inform, there are effectively entirely separate languages Inform 6 and Inform 7, so we should probably use separate inform6 and inform7 tags. (I've now retagged the Inform 7 questions).</description>
<category>Meta</category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ifanswers.com/12/do-questions-on-development-tool-need-to-mention-the-version?show=15#a15</guid>
<pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2015 00:29:15 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Answered: What is IF Answers?</title>
<link>http://ifanswers.com/1/what-is-if-answers?show=2#a2</link>
<description>&lt;p&gt;IF Answers exists because I've believed for some time that it would be great if we had a Stack Exchange site for Interactive Fiction - i.e. a site where questions and answers can be voted on and edited by the community (like &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;http://stackoverflow.com&quot;&gt;Stack Overflow&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There have been a &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;http://www.intfiction.org/forum/viewtopic.php?f=4&amp;amp;t=12407&quot;&gt;couple of attempts&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;at getting an Interactive Fiction Stack Exchange site set up, but they didn't get enough traction to get going.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It's kind of a chicken-and-egg thing really. I think an IF Q&amp;amp;A site will only gain momentum after it starts&amp;nbsp;existing - before that happens,&amp;nbsp;there aren't enough of us who really &quot;get&quot; the idea yet to get one started via the Stack Exchange Area 51 process. (And even though I happen to be an employee of Stack Exchange myself, I have no influence over what sites get set up).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fortunately, there's an open source platform called &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;http://www.question2answer.org/&quot;&gt;Question2Answer&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;which allows you to create Stack Exchange-style sites, so that's what I've set up here at ifanswers.com.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Things that are on-topic here:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Technical questions about interactive fiction&amp;nbsp;development tools such as&amp;nbsp;Inform, Twine, Quest, QuestKit, Squiffy,&amp;nbsp;Adrift, TADS&amp;nbsp;etc. are&amp;nbsp;all on-topic here.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Non-technical questions about interactive fiction are also on-topic. These questions could be about general IF design,&amp;nbsp;specific games, entering the IF Comp etc.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<category>Meta</category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ifanswers.com/1/what-is-if-answers?show=2#a2</guid>
<pubDate>Sun, 22 Mar 2015 10:41:22 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>