<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>IF Answers - Recent questions tagged css</title>
<link>http://ifanswers.com/tag/css</link>
<description>Powered by Question2Answer</description>
<item>
<title>Can you use custom CSS files with games uploaded to textadvenures.co.uk?</title>
<link>http://ifanswers.com/752/can-you-use-custom-files-with-games-uploaded-textadvenures</link>
<description>&lt;p&gt;I released an Inform 7 game along with the Quixe  interpreter and set up a custom CSS file for it in the Interpreter folder. On my computer the stylesheet works, but when I zip the release folder and upload it to  textadventures.co.uk, playing it online brings up the default stylesheet.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<category>Publishing</category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ifanswers.com/752/can-you-use-custom-files-with-games-uploaded-textadvenures</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2015 10:59:45 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>How to show window background color in Quixe: background color property or text background? (Flexible Windows, Inform 7)</title>
<link>http://ifanswers.com/741/background-background-property-background-flexible-windows</link>
<description>&lt;p&gt;I know you can use a custom CSS style sheet to set two custom text styles in Quixe. But I'm not sure if there's a way to make the background color &lt;em&gt;property&lt;/em&gt; show the appropriate custom color in Quixe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even if there is, I'm thinking using the text style (rather than using the actual background color property) may be the better way to go to specify a background color for a window, because then one of the styles in the CSS style sheet can be customized to reflect both background color and text color.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, defining a named custom style &quot;uses up&quot; one of the two style slots that the story author has available, and so maybe that would be a disadvantage if the author has other text styles they want to use for other things. (Unless the background color property also &quot;uses up&quot; one of the two custom style slots?)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<category>Authoring</category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ifanswers.com/741/background-background-property-background-flexible-windows</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2015 16:40:21 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Twine with sugarcube: can you display visited links differently?</title>
<link>http://ifanswers.com/477/twine-with-sugarcube-you-display-visited-links-differently</link>
<description>&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;http://twinery.org/&quot;&gt;Twine&lt;/a&gt; (1.4) using the &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;http://www.motoslave.net/sugarcube/&quot;&gt;Sugarcube&lt;/a&gt; story format, is there some way to display links to visited passages so they look different from unvisited links? They are &quot;a&quot; html anchors, but using a an &lt;code&gt;a:visited&lt;/code&gt; css selector does not cut it, I assume because the linking is done using javascript &quot;click&quot; events, not standard browser linking.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<category>Authoring</category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ifanswers.com/477/twine-with-sugarcube-you-display-visited-links-differently</guid>
<pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2015 07:27:23 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>How can I modify or create new status panes?</title>
<link>http://ifanswers.com/461/how-can-i-modify-or-create-new-status-panes</link>
<description>&lt;p&gt;I want to modify the panes on the right of the Quest user interface.&lt;br&gt;
I'd like it to display some extra information, or images, or something of that nature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example I'd like to show an icon next to items in the inventory, or to display a portrait of the character in the status pane.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can't seem to track down what actually sends any of the CSS or JS info to them however. (In fact, some of the style IDs listed in the HTML Helper don't seem to appear in any quest files at all according to a mass file search!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I've also been considering attempting some semblance of a healthbar, but I'll get to that later, once I actually figure out how to do anything at all to the panes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most important thing is, I'd like to be able to inject different things based on Quest object attributes, so just setting up static styles for the panes won't be enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even if it's nothing more than using square bullet points for some objects and diamond ones for others, it would be a start.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<category>Authoring</category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ifanswers.com/461/how-can-i-modify-or-create-new-status-panes</guid>
<pubDate>Sat, 11 Apr 2015 06:47:47 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>How do I skin the Quest player UI?</title>
<link>http://ifanswers.com/445/how-do-i-skin-the-quest-player-ui</link>
<description>&lt;p&gt;I know changing the UI style in offline mode is a different process from changing it in online mode...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I don't entirely grasp the process differences individually.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I wanted to create a new UI style (not simply changing colors around, but actually using new images and button skins and such) what file would I need to change/include?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Would that automatically be included when I uploaded the game?&lt;br&gt;
Would I need to change any significant code, or will CSS be enough?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<category>Authoring</category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ifanswers.com/445/how-do-i-skin-the-quest-player-ui</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2015 01:44:07 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Is there a way to reduce the right margin for a play-in-browser website released by Inform 7?</title>
<link>http://ifanswers.com/387/there-reduce-right-margin-browser-website-released-inform</link>
<description>&lt;p&gt;When you choose to release a game with a website and interpreter in Inform 7, it generates two pages: index.html and play.html.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The index page looks nice. The text has a preset width and stops far away from the right margin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But with the play page, the text has a wrap-around effect and it runs all the way to the right margin, which I don't think looks any good. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This question probably isn't related to Inform at all, and I imagine you have to edit the CSS files somehow. I'm a complete amateur. Any help would be appreciated!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<category>Authoring</category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ifanswers.com/387/there-reduce-right-margin-browser-website-released-inform</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2015 15:39:27 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>