<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>IF Answers - Recent questions tagged flexible-windows</title>
<link>http://ifanswers.com/tag/flexible-windows</link>
<description>Powered by Question2Answer</description>
<item>
<title>How does one change the User Style for hyperlinks when using Flexible Windows?</title>
<link>http://ifanswers.com/1218/does-change-user-style-hyperlinks-when-using-flexible-windows</link>
<description>&lt;p&gt;I've been setting up all the styles for text (using Table of User Styles (continued) in my source, but haven't been able to figure out the style name for hyperlinks..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I'm primarily just trying to remove the blue colour to black, to match the rest of the text - remaining underlined is fine (though not preferable).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If there's no style name for hyperlinks (which is what I'm guessing now), how would one go about changing this font colour?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<category>Authoring</category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ifanswers.com/1218/does-change-user-style-hyperlinks-when-using-flexible-windows</guid>
<pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2015 05:05:28 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Using the Flexible Windows extension, how can I depict a scaled image in my graphics window?</title>
<link>http://ifanswers.com/933/flexible-windows-extension-depict-scaled-graphics-window</link>
<description>&lt;p&gt;My game was working fine with Flexible Windows until something, somewhere broke it (it gave me errors when running, though both the I7- and I6-compilers ran fine). I updated the plugin and, after updating loads of others (dependencies, like Glulx Text Effects), finally got the thing to compile again. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, the plugin has been rewritten from scratch in the meantime, improving or simplifying it in some ways but also taking away some functions (such as bordered windows). &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Previously, I could display figures in the main window using Inform's standard &quot;display&quot;action, and depict them, scaled to fit, in my graphics window using the Flexible Windows &quot;depict&quot; action that was in one of the examples.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That 'depict' code no longer works. When compiling, the I6 compiler gives two errors:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;auto.inf(61696): Error:  No such constant as &quot;WindowSize&quot;
auto.inf(61717): Error:  No such constant as &quot;ref_number&quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the lump of mostly I6 code that hooks into the older version of Flexible Windows, but can't anymore because it's been rewritten.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;To depict (f - a figure-name):
    now the current image is f;
    follow the window-drawing rules for the graphics-window.

Window-drawing rule for the graphics-window (this is the draw scaled image rule):
    if graphics-window is g-unpresent, rule fails;
    clear the graphics-window;
    draw scaled copy of current image in graphics-window.

To draw scaled copy of (f - a figure-name) in (g - a g-window):
    (- DrawScaled({f}, {g}); -).

Include (-

    ! Doing scaling calculations in I6 lets us handle bigger numbers

    [ GetImageSize curimg index result;
        result = glk_image_get_info( ResourceIDsOfFigures--&amp;gt;curimg, gg_arguments, gg_arguments+WORDSIZE);
        return gg_arguments--&amp;gt;index;
    ];

    [ DrawScaled figure g w_total h_total graph_height graph_width w_offset h_offset;
    graph_height = WindowSize(g, 1);
    graph_width = gg_arguments--&amp;gt;0;
    w_total = GetImageSize(figure, 0);
    h_total = gg_arguments--&amp;gt;1;

    if (graph_height - h_total &amp;lt; 0) ! if the image won't fit, find the scaling factor
    {
        w_total = (graph_height * w_total)/h_total;
        h_total = graph_height;

    }

    if (graph_width - w_total &amp;lt; 0)
    {
        h_total = (graph_width * h_total)/w_total;
        w_total = graph_width;
    }

    w_offset = (graph_width - w_total)/2; if (w_offset &amp;lt; 0) w_offset = 0;
    h_offset = (graph_height - h_total)/2; if (h_offset &amp;lt; 0) h_offset = 0;

    glk_image_draw_scaled(g.ref_number, ResourceIDsOfFigures--&amp;gt;figure, w_offset, h_offset, w_total, h_total);
    ];

-).
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I'm not able to write I6 code myself, my question is as follows: how do I modify this code to work with &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/i7/extensions/blob/master/Jon%20Ingold/Flexible%20Windows.i7x&quot;&gt;the most recent version of Flexible Windows from Github&lt;/a&gt;, or what different code can I use to get the same results?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<category>Authoring</category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ifanswers.com/933/flexible-windows-extension-depict-scaled-graphics-window</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2015 13:25:22 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>How do you test whether the player's interpreter will support windows created with Flexible Windows? (Inform 7)</title>
<link>http://ifanswers.com/778/whether-players-interpreter-support-created-flexible-windows</link>
<description>&lt;p&gt;So, e.g., in Parchment, you'd be able to display a message that says &quot;Your interpreter does not support this feature.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<category>Authoring</category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ifanswers.com/778/whether-players-interpreter-support-created-flexible-windows</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2015 13:21:15 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>How do you use a hyperlink to paste text without (in effect) pressing enter? (Flexible Windows, Inform 7)</title>
<link>http://ifanswers.com/750/hyperlink-without-effect-pressing-flexible-windows-inform</link>
<description>&lt;p&gt;I'd like to use hyperlinks to paste partial commands at the prompt, and allow the player to finish typing the command, but when I use the built-in hyperlink behavior of Flexible Windows, clicking the link automatically submits the text as a complete command. Is there a way to just paste the text and leave it be?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<category>Authoring</category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ifanswers.com/750/hyperlink-without-effect-pressing-flexible-windows-inform</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2015 02:58:34 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>How to show window background color in Quixe: background color property or text background? (Flexible Windows, Inform 7)</title>
<link>http://ifanswers.com/741/background-background-property-background-flexible-windows</link>
<description>&lt;p&gt;I know you can use a custom CSS style sheet to set two custom text styles in Quixe. But I'm not sure if there's a way to make the background color &lt;em&gt;property&lt;/em&gt; show the appropriate custom color in Quixe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even if there is, I'm thinking using the text style (rather than using the actual background color property) may be the better way to go to specify a background color for a window, because then one of the styles in the CSS style sheet can be customized to reflect both background color and text color.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, defining a named custom style &quot;uses up&quot; one of the two style slots that the story author has available, and so maybe that would be a disadvantage if the author has other text styles they want to use for other things. (Unless the background color property also &quot;uses up&quot; one of the two custom style slots?)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<category>Authoring</category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ifanswers.com/741/background-background-property-background-flexible-windows</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2015 16:40:21 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>With Flexible Windows, can you specify whether a window will have a scroll bar? (Inform 7)</title>
<link>http://ifanswers.com/740/with-flexible-windows-specify-whether-window-scroll-inform</link>
<description>&lt;p&gt;It looks as though Quixe (and the Inform IDE) shows a scroll bar by default for a text window, and Glulxe and Gargoyle do not show a scroll bar. Is showing or not showing a scroll bar something under the story author's control, or is it dependent on the player's interpreter settings?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<category>Authoring</category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ifanswers.com/740/with-flexible-windows-specify-whether-window-scroll-inform</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2015 16:02:49 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>In Flexible Windows, is it acceptable to set, e.g., the window position at or after the start of play? (Inform 7)</title>
<link>http://ifanswers.com/709/flexible-windows-acceptable-window-position-after-inform</link>
<description>&lt;p&gt;With the extension Flexible Windows by Jon Ingold, is it okay to set attributes of the window at the start of play, or even after the start of play, as long as they are set before the window is opened for the first time? Documentation of the original extension seemed to say that changing some things during play could cause bugs (with restoring, for instance) so I wasn't sure what the boundaries are.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<category>Authoring</category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ifanswers.com/709/flexible-windows-acceptable-window-position-after-inform</guid>
<pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 22:04:46 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>How do you avoid an extra line break when refreshing a window with Flexible Windows (Inform 7)?</title>
<link>http://ifanswers.com/690/avoid-extra-break-refreshing-window-flexible-windows-inform</link>
<description>&lt;p&gt;This&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Include Flexible Windows by Jon Ingold.

The sidebar is a g-window.
The main window spawns the sidebar.
The scale method of the sidebar is g-fixed-size.
The measurement of the sidebar is 40.
The position of the sidebar is g-placeleft.

Every turn while the sidebar is g-present:
    Refresh the sidebar.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;works fine. But adding this&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Rule for refreshing the sidebar:
    say &quot;Text.&quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adds an extra line break in the main window every turn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How can I avoid this? It reminds me of &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;http://www.intfiction.org/forum/viewtopic.php?f=7&amp;amp;t=17446&amp;amp;p=87531&quot;&gt;this rulebook break issue&lt;/a&gt; but I'm not sure if it's related.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<category>Authoring</category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ifanswers.com/690/avoid-extra-break-refreshing-window-flexible-windows-inform</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2015 17:16:52 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>With Flexible Windows by Jon Ingold, is there a way to make the text display at the top of the window, even in Gargoyle? (Inform 7)</title>
<link>http://ifanswers.com/688/flexible-windows-ingold-there-display-window-gargoyle-inform</link>
<description>&lt;p&gt;If you create a text window, can you make the text align with the top of the window instead of the bottom, even in Gargoyle?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<category>Authoring</category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ifanswers.com/688/flexible-windows-ingold-there-display-window-gargoyle-inform</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2015 14:26:25 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>With Flexible Windows, can I make the background color of one window always match another one? (Inform 7)</title>
<link>http://ifanswers.com/662/flexible-windows-background-window-always-another-inform</link>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Is there a way to make the background color of window X always reflect the background color of window Y, even if the color of window Y gets changed?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using this as a starting point&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Include version 15/150128 of Flexible Windows by Jon Ingold.

The side window is a g-window spawned by the main window.
The position of the side window is g-placeright.
The scale method of the side window is g-proportional.
The measurement of the side window is 33.

Toggling the side window is an action out of world.
Understand &quot;side window&quot; as toggling the side window.

Carry out toggling the side window:
    if the side window is g-present:
        close the side window;
    otherwise:
        open the side window.

The border window is a graphics g-window spawned by the side window.
The position of the border window is g-placeleft.
The scale method of the border window is g-fixed-size.
The measurement of the border window is 20.

After constructing the side window:
    open the border window;

Rule for refreshing the side window:
    say &quot;This should be indented.[line break]So should this.&quot;

Table of User Styles (continued)
window (a g-window) background color (a text)
side window &quot;607080&quot;

Place is a room.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I added this, which didn't compile:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;The background color of the border window is the background color of the side window.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and when I tried this&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;The background color of the border window is &quot;[background color of the side window]&quot;.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;it compiled but did not make the colors match.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<category>Authoring</category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ifanswers.com/662/flexible-windows-background-window-always-another-inform</guid>
<pubDate>Sun, 24 May 2015 20:44:11 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>How do you indent text in a window using Flexible Windows by Jon Ingold? (Inform 7)</title>
<link>http://ifanswers.com/641/you-indent-text-window-using-flexible-windows-ingold-inform</link>
<description>&lt;p&gt;I'm trying to indent the text in the window by changing the &quot;indentation&quot; entry in the Table of User styles, but it doesn't seem to affect anything. How would I do this?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Include version 15/150128 of Flexible Windows by Jon Ingold.

The side window is a g-window spawned by the main window.
The position of the side window is g-placeright.
The scale method of the side window is g-proportional.
The measurement of the side window is 33.

Toggling the side window is an action out of world.
Understand &quot;side window&quot; as toggling the side window.

Carry out toggling the side window:
    if the side window is g-present:
        close the side window;
    otherwise:
        open the side window.

Rule for refreshing the side window:
    say &quot;This should be indented.[line break]So should this.&quot;

Table of User Styles (continued)
window (a g-window) style name (a glulx text style) background color (a text)   color (a text)  first line indentation (a number)   fixed width (a truth state) font weight (a font weight) indentation (a number)  italic (a truth state)  justification (a text justification)    relative size (a number)    reversed (a truth state)
side window --  --  --  --  --  --  10  --  --  --  --

Place is a room.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or maybe what I'm looking for isn't technically indentation, but a margin, so the text isn't right up against the edge of the window. Is that possible?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<category>Authoring</category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ifanswers.com/641/you-indent-text-window-using-flexible-windows-ingold-inform</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 22 May 2015 15:27:24 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>In Inform 7, how do you create a text window using Flexible Windows by Jon Ingold?</title>
<link>http://ifanswers.com/634/inform-create-text-window-using-flexible-windows-jon-ingold</link>
<description>&lt;p&gt;The Flexible Windows extension is &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/i7/extensions/master/Jon%20Ingold/Flexible%20Windows.i7x&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Would someone please give an example of how to create a text window to the left or right of the main window? I'd also like to know how to  show and hide the window during play.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<category>Authoring</category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ifanswers.com/634/inform-create-text-window-using-flexible-windows-jon-ingold</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2015 17:51:21 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>