<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>IF Answers - Recent questions tagged if-script</title>
<link>http://ifanswers.com/tag/if-script</link>
<description>Powered by Question2Answer</description>
<item>
<title>Quest: if's, exits, blocking and attributes</title>
<link>http://ifanswers.com/1254/quest-ifs-exits-blocking-and-attributes</link>
<description>&lt;p&gt;So these forums have been very useful, thanks a ton for that.&lt;br&gt;
I've tried using gamebook version, but it seems rather limited, and I couldn't find dictionary functions to make attributes work properly and still so much more the text version does better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking for Text Adventure Answers please**&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So First Question is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How do you make page links available if a stat is high enough?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;{if player.cunning&amp;gt;25:}&lt;br&gt;
I want the following to be displayed&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;{command:go to Room4: So cunning you get to go here!}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I'm adding the commands to the text description, and I can't quite get it right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second Question:&lt;br&gt;
The next thing I am having trouble with is blocking a path (exit) after it has been used. &lt;br&gt;
Player has a choice of going to Room2, Room3, or Room4, player can't go to Room4 till their cunning is increased, so that isn't displayed yet, So player picks Room2, then Room2 links back to the Original Room1, but now I want Room2 to be blocked, that choice has already been taken and is no longer valid. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I've dabbled in exits and if's there as well, but can't quite get that right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last Question (For Now)&lt;br&gt;
How do you display stats on a page without using the show panes interface? I'm looking to make it feel like more of a choose your own adventure, but with stats still recorded and shown.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hopefully want it in descriptions, or maybe at header.&lt;br&gt;
 Maybe there is a way to have the option to remove inventory, compass, place and objects from the screen, but keep status?  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any answer, would be very useful, thanks.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<category>Authoring</category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ifanswers.com/1254/quest-ifs-exits-blocking-and-attributes</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 23 Oct 2015 16:06:51 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>I want to make a verb that requires to things at once. How do I do this this? [internet version]</title>
<link>http://ifanswers.com/1110/want-make-that-requires-things-once-this-this-internet-version</link>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Specifically, I want it to be that the player can only skin the wolf if:&lt;br&gt;
1. The wolf is dead&lt;br&gt;
AND&lt;br&gt;
2. The player has a stone&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using flags, I can make the wolf dead, and I can make it so that the wolf must be dead for skinning. I can also make it so that a stone is needed for skinning. The problem is, I cannot make it so that BOTH of these is required. Any help is welcome, thanks in advance&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-- Plink333&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<category>Authoring</category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ifanswers.com/1110/want-make-that-requires-things-once-this-this-internet-version</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2015 16:57:01 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Quest Gamebook: How to use AND OR and NOT inside an &quot;if&quot; command?</title>
<link>http://ifanswers.com/945/quest-gamebook-how-to-use-and-or-and-not-inside-an-if-command</link>
<description>&lt;p&gt;I am using a system where flags are set on as certain conversations are had, and then these flags are used later to make various characters dynamically aware of what has happened before, or to make some links inactive if certain conditions are or are not met. I was previously under the impression that I could use AND, OR, and NOT inside an 'if' command with impunity, but lately something hasn't been working right with an OR command. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I have a room in which there are three people and you have options to go talk to each one and then possibly leave with them, depending on conditions. So when you talk to person 1, it sets a personone flag on. Person three is really picky about whether you've talked to the others, so I want him to react as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you go to him after talking to ONE of the others, he will talk to you, but only grudginly: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;{if personone or persontwo:&quot;Okay fine, I guess.&quot;}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you go to him after talking to the others, he's more receptive: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;{if personone and persontwo:&quot;Yeah, you can come with me.&quot;}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you go to him first, he outright rejects your attempts to talk: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;{if not personone and not persontwo:&quot;Go away!&quot;}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the problem I'm having is that it keeps going to the reject option when I have talked to ONE of the others. I thought that I could use the OR command to tell it to activate that option when only one of the things is true but not the other, but it detects that one of the flags isn't there and picks only the reject option. Am I going to need to nest IF commands: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;{if personone:{if not persontwo:&quot;Okay fine, I guess.&quot;}}{if persontwo:{if not personone:&quot;Okay fine, I guess.&quot;}}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or is there an easier way to do this?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for any help you can offer. I'm not having luck finding it in the documentation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<category>Authoring</category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ifanswers.com/945/quest-gamebook-how-to-use-and-or-and-not-inside-an-if-command</guid>
<pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2015 05:30:49 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Quest Gamebook: Return to a previous page with multiple links, and make link already chosen inactive</title>
<link>http://ifanswers.com/935/gamebook-return-previous-multiple-already-chosen-inactive</link>
<description>&lt;p&gt;I'm new to Quest and know next to nothing about programming. I'm trying my best, but sometimes it all sounds like gibberish to me. I tried to search the forums for an answer to my probably simple question, but I think I ended up confusing myself even more. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I'm trying to figure out the easiest way to basically backtrack and then block out a link from a list of options when you reach that page again. For example, the player can choose to sneak into the kitchen, talk to a barmaid, or talk to an adventurer. Say the player sneaks into the kitchen first, finds out what he/she needs to, but then has nowhere else to go. So they go back out to the tavern scene they started at, and from there, I want the other two options to be still available, while the first one no longer be a clickable link (or if you click it, it gives you a message that you've already done everything here or something and takes you back to the other options again).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I've tried the &quot;If&quot; script hoping that I can tag each link when a player first chooses that option. Then if the player has seen the page/has a counter, when they get back to the the page that has all the choices, the link they already have followed is just text. Or if they haven't seen that page/have that counter, the link is still viable. That didn't seem to work for multiple &quot;the player has already seen page if&quot; options. It seemed to only spit out the message for the page they did see and didn't show the link for the pages they player hadn't already seen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I'm wondering if I could somehow use the &quot;first time&quot; script instead to get an active link to disappear after the player has already chosen it and then circled back? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, I was wondering if somebody could explain the &quot;Add page link&quot; script, because I think I'm confusing myself over that as well. Every time I try to use it, I get nothing when I try to play through the game. (Or maybe I'm just using it wrong. I was trying to use it above with the &quot;if&quot; script. For example, if have seen page, display message. But if not seen page, add active link for an option for the player to pick.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for any help, and patience, you can offer this confused newbie!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<category>Authoring</category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ifanswers.com/935/gamebook-return-previous-multiple-already-chosen-inactive</guid>
<pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2015 05:38:09 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>