<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>IF Answers - Recent questions tagged inventory</title>
<link>http://ifanswers.com/tag/inventory</link>
<description>Powered by Question2Answer</description>
<item>
<title>Quest: &quot;Check Inventory&quot;</title>
<link>http://ifanswers.com/889/quest-check-inventory</link>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Hey All,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I'm trying to make a Command in quest, where the player can type Check Inventory, and it will list the player inventory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Only problem is, I'm used to only using the basics of the Quest program, and I know nothing about 'Variable, Object, Attribute and Function' which I assume have something to do with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyone got any advice?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reason I'm doing this, is because I want to use the 'Retro' theme, and get rid of the pane at the right, as it does not blend in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anna&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<category>Authoring</category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ifanswers.com/889/quest-check-inventory</guid>
<pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2015 20:00:23 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Stopping a message from being said multiple times (Inform 7)?</title>
<link>http://ifanswers.com/573/stopping-a-message-from-being-said-multiple-times-inform-7</link>
<description>&lt;p&gt;My code is probably pretty atrocious because I'm just learning Inform 7 and messing around by expanding some of the examples in the documentation, so pardon that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a case which contains multiple fishing rods and I don't want the player to be able to take a second one if they've already got one in their inventory, so this is the code I've written:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Before taking a fishing rod:
    if the player carries a fishing rod:
        say &quot;You only need one fishing rod.&quot;;
        stop the action.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This works really well unless the player wants to take more than one fishing rod at once. If, for instance, the player types &quot;take all fishing rods&quot;, it will only place one in their inventory, but it will print out one success message and then a message of &quot;You only need one fishing rod&quot; for each remaining fishing rod in the case.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;fishing rod: Taken.
fishing rod: You only need one fishing rod.
fishing rod: You only need one fishing rod.
fishing rod: You only need one fishing rod.
fishing rod: You only need one fishing rod.
fishing rod: You only need one fishing rod.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This isn't world-ending, especially since there are only six, but it is a little sloppy. Is there a way to stop it after one print and/or a better way around it? The examples in the documentation about dispensers weren't very helpful because I want the case to have a finite number of fishing rods.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<category>Authoring</category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ifanswers.com/573/stopping-a-message-from-being-said-multiple-times-inform-7</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2015 20:17:21 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Is there a standard way to deal with stacks of items, i.e., having 13 health potions or 6 flowers?</title>
<link>http://ifanswers.com/209/there-standard-stacks-items-having-health-potions-flowers</link>
<description>I've seen item properties like, &amp;quot;there is a small amount of widgets here.&amp;quot; but it doesn't really work for more specific operations. For instance, if I eat one apple and I have 5, I would expect to have four afterwords. I'd also expect to have 5 apples again if I find another apple of the same kind somewhere else. I would imagine that there's some obvious built-in utility or extension for this sort of thing, but I can't find it. Any ideas?</description>
<category>Authoring</category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ifanswers.com/209/there-standard-stacks-items-having-health-potions-flowers</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2015 00:27:33 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>