<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>IF Answers - Recent questions tagged textadventures-co-uk</title>
<link>http://ifanswers.com/tag/textadventures-co-uk</link>
<description>Powered by Question2Answer</description>
<item>
<title>Selling games?</title>
<link>http://ifanswers.com/1212/selling-games</link>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Basically, it says you can sell the games you make. So can the windows version export EXE's or something? Thanks!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<category>Publishing</category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ifanswers.com/1212/selling-games</guid>
<pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2015 02:40:44 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Can I share an unfinished game?</title>
<link>http://ifanswers.com/1032/can-i-share-an-unfinished-game</link>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Is there a way that I can share an unfinished story with friends so that they can play the game without me having to publish it fully?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<category>Publishing</category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ifanswers.com/1032/can-i-share-an-unfinished-game</guid>
<pubDate>Sun, 09 Aug 2015 03:07:28 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>I accidentally deleted a game, can I somehow recover it?</title>
<link>http://ifanswers.com/957/i-accidentally-deleted-a-game-can-i-somehow-recover-it</link>
<description>&lt;p&gt;I accidentally deleted a game on textadventures.co.uk because I thought it was a different game. &lt;br&gt;
I've worked really hard on it, and I was wondering if there was a way to recover it. &lt;br&gt;
Please help me, I don't want to start over.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<category>Authoring</category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ifanswers.com/957/i-accidentally-deleted-a-game-can-i-somehow-recover-it</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2015 03:05:52 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Upload a game from Inklewriter</title>
<link>http://ifanswers.com/931/upload-a-game-from-inklewriter</link>
<description>&lt;p&gt;I've seen people uploading text adventures from inklewriter to textadventures.co.uk, and I want to know how to do that. Can someone help me, please?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<category>Publishing</category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ifanswers.com/931/upload-a-game-from-inklewriter</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2015 02:13:58 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>&quot;invalid ID&quot; error</title>
<link>http://ifanswers.com/905/invalid-id-error</link>
<description>&lt;p&gt;This has been happening with me for a few games I made, and every time, I had to remake it. But its happening again!! It tells me an invalid ID error message when I wanted to edit the game I am working on. Please help me.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<category>Authoring</category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ifanswers.com/905/invalid-id-error</guid>
<pubDate>Sat, 11 Jul 2015 00:56:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Which textadventures.co.uk category would best fit a stock market-like game?</title>
<link>http://ifanswers.com/828/which-textadventures-category-would-stock-market-like-game</link>
<description>&lt;p&gt;It's, definitely, educational and simulation but since I'm limited to 1 category on textadventures, what do you think I should put it under when I'm ready to publish it?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<category>Publishing</category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ifanswers.com/828/which-textadventures-category-would-stock-market-like-game</guid>
<pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2015 21:15:44 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>How do you make choices in Quest?</title>
<link>http://ifanswers.com/763/how-do-you-make-choices-in-quest</link>
<description>&lt;p&gt;I'm currently working on a text game in Quest, however I was wondering how you make a sort of multiple choice dialogue list.  Like, a list of hyperlinks that lead to different paths of dialouge.  I know it seems like a simple question, but the process of solving it has evaded me.  Thank you in advance to whoever answers my question.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<category>Authoring</category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ifanswers.com/763/how-do-you-make-choices-in-quest</guid>
<pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2015 03:42:06 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Can you use custom CSS files with games uploaded to textadvenures.co.uk?</title>
<link>http://ifanswers.com/752/can-you-use-custom-files-with-games-uploaded-textadvenures</link>
<description>&lt;p&gt;I released an Inform 7 game along with the Quixe  interpreter and set up a custom CSS file for it in the Interpreter folder. On my computer the stylesheet works, but when I zip the release folder and upload it to  textadventures.co.uk, playing it online brings up the default stylesheet.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<category>Publishing</category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ifanswers.com/752/can-you-use-custom-files-with-games-uploaded-textadvenures</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2015 10:59:45 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Can I edit a game that I have already published?</title>
<link>http://ifanswers.com/599/can-i-edit-a-game-that-i-have-already-published</link>
<description>
</description>
<category>Publishing</category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ifanswers.com/599/can-i-edit-a-game-that-i-have-already-published</guid>
<pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2015 17:36:53 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Stupid Reviews on My Game!</title>
<link>http://ifanswers.com/485/stupid-reviews-on-my-game</link>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Hi there,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I made a text adventure on The Stanley Parable last year, and ever since,  I've been getting a few bad reviews from it simply because... get this... it wasn't the actual Stanley Parable game! Yes! Kids (I assume) come to my game thinking it is the real thing, and when they find it's not (big surprise), they give bad reviews and comments and usually vote it 0-2 stars! I am outraged that they think they can do this to me and it really hurts to see a game I worked on for so long is being bashed for really no reason at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is there any kind of response mechanism I can use to reply to these bastards? I can't just sit back and take this!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nintendex&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<category>Publishing</category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ifanswers.com/485/stupid-reviews-on-my-game</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2015 10:46:48 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Why is my game still &quot;unlisted&quot; on textadventures.co.uk?</title>
<link>http://ifanswers.com/444/why-is-my-game-still-unlisted-on-textadventures-co-uk</link>
<description>&lt;p&gt;I have a game on the Text Adventures called &quot;Wandering and Shrinking (1.0.1)&quot;, however I could never tell if it was ever actually uploaded.  Whenever I went to edit the game and make sure it was visible, it defaulted to &quot;unlisted&quot;.  I repeatedly set it to public, but I was never sure if it was really public.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I decided to try editing my profile, since I also have an issue where I do not have a profile picture like everyone else.  I made a new password, and suddenly when I went to check my games, the game had gone missing from my list!  It apparently had made a new profile for my new password (which is a load of malarkey) and I had to relog in with my Google account, since that was what I had used originally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of these issues have simply baffled me, and I am really interested in using this web service.  Can somebody explain to me what might be happening?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<category>Publishing</category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ifanswers.com/444/why-is-my-game-still-unlisted-on-textadventures-co-uk</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2015 23:30:59 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>