<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>IF Answers - Recent questions in Publishing</title>
<link>http://ifanswers.com/questions/publishing</link>
<description>Powered by Question2Answer</description>
<item>
<title>How do I delete a game from the whole website?</title>
<link>http://ifanswers.com/1228/how-do-i-delete-a-game-from-the-whole-website</link>
<description>&lt;p&gt;I have a game I published to Textadventures,But need to delete it completely from the web.How do I do that?I use quest.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<category>Publishing</category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ifanswers.com/1228/how-do-i-delete-a-game-from-the-whole-website</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2015 00:13:36 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Selling games?</title>
<link>http://ifanswers.com/1212/selling-games</link>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Basically, it says you can sell the games you make. So can the windows version export EXE's or something? Thanks!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<category>Publishing</category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ifanswers.com/1212/selling-games</guid>
<pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2015 02:40:44 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>No option to save a .quest file?</title>
<link>http://ifanswers.com/1176/no-option-to-save-a-quest-file</link>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Hi everyone. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is my first time using Quest, so I apologize if this question has been asked and/or answered before. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spent about 5 days coding a storybook on the offline Quest editor, and when I finalized everything this afternoon, I clicked the publish option to finally upload it. However, when I went to save it from a .aslx file to a .quest file, it didn't give me an option to save at all. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the window that the editor gives me: &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;http://prntscr.com/8flx9o&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without the option to save the .quest file, I'm not too sure how to go about uploading it. If you have any idea about how to fix this, please let me know! Thank you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<category>Publishing</category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ifanswers.com/1176/no-option-to-save-a-quest-file</guid>
<pubDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2015 20:27:47 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>How to make pictures show up when playing online.</title>
<link>http://ifanswers.com/1162/how-to-make-pictures-show-up-when-playing-online</link>
<description>&lt;p&gt;I recently submitted a game to IFComp, and I noticed when trying the 'play online' option that pictures aren't showing up -- instead I get lines that say [Picture 3 goes here], etc.  The file should include the proper materials (they show up fine in the download version), so I'm not sure why they're not appearing when playing online.  Has anyone else experienced this issue?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<category>Publishing</category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ifanswers.com/1162/how-to-make-pictures-show-up-when-playing-online</guid>
<pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2015 20:37:45 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Can I supply my own CSS to the gs.tads.io server / interpreter?</title>
<link>http://ifanswers.com/1158/can-i-supply-my-own-css-to-the-gs-tads-io-server-interpreter</link>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Now that I know that I can &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;http://ifanswers.com/774/there-javascript-interpreter-for-tads-that-can-run-website&quot;&gt;straight up send the gs.tads.io server my games&lt;/a&gt;, can I change the output in any way, or am I stuck with it's fonts, colors, etc.?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<category>Publishing</category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ifanswers.com/1158/can-i-supply-my-own-css-to-the-gs-tads-io-server-interpreter</guid>
<pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2015 06:37:15 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Does Squiffy use the same MIT licence as Quest?</title>
<link>http://ifanswers.com/1136/does-squiffy-use-the-same-mit-licence-as-quest</link>
<description>&lt;p&gt;The Squiffy page doesn't seem to indicate what licence the software is under.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<category>Publishing</category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ifanswers.com/1136/does-squiffy-use-the-same-mit-licence-as-quest</guid>
<pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2015 12:23:09 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Can I share an unfinished game?</title>
<link>http://ifanswers.com/1032/can-i-share-an-unfinished-game</link>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Is there a way that I can share an unfinished story with friends so that they can play the game without me having to publish it fully?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<category>Publishing</category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ifanswers.com/1032/can-i-share-an-unfinished-game</guid>
<pubDate>Sun, 09 Aug 2015 03:07:28 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Upload a game from Inklewriter</title>
<link>http://ifanswers.com/931/upload-a-game-from-inklewriter</link>
<description>&lt;p&gt;I've seen people uploading text adventures from inklewriter to textadventures.co.uk, and I want to know how to do that. Can someone help me, please?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<category>Publishing</category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ifanswers.com/931/upload-a-game-from-inklewriter</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2015 02:13:58 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Ascii Art, Images and Music when publishing</title>
<link>http://ifanswers.com/913/ascii-art-images-and-music-when-publishing</link>
<description>&lt;p&gt;I assume the main places for publishing IF are through the text adventures site, through ifdb (often played through frotz) or as a separate website or app(converting html to an app).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was wondering about using images, ascii art and music across different publishing platforms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Does Frotz for iphone, iPad and Android support audio? I haven't played any IF that has used sound , images or ascii art using Frotz but I was unsure?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am considering building a text adenture that uses lots of glitchy electronic music in different sections but wanted to find out if it would translate across different platforms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Has anyone tried making a quest game (with music or images), changing the html to an app through 'Phonegap'. Have you had any success with this? I was just keen to explore this and wondered if anyone had tried it so I could learn from any mistakes or limitations.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<category>Publishing</category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ifanswers.com/913/ascii-art-images-and-music-when-publishing</guid>
<pubDate>Sun, 12 Jul 2015 04:06:40 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Which textadventures.co.uk category would best fit a stock market-like game?</title>
<link>http://ifanswers.com/828/which-textadventures-category-would-stock-market-like-game</link>
<description>&lt;p&gt;It's, definitely, educational and simulation but since I'm limited to 1 category on textadventures, what do you think I should put it under when I'm ready to publish it?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<category>Publishing</category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ifanswers.com/828/which-textadventures-category-would-stock-market-like-game</guid>
<pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2015 21:15:44 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>QuestJS asked for a .quest file and when I save my Quest adventure it saves as a .aslx file</title>
<link>http://ifanswers.com/813/questjs-asked-quest-file-save-quest-adventure-saves-aslx-file</link>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Is .quest from an older version of Quest? I havn't tried the online converter. Sure would like to get it working though :&amp;lt;(&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<category>Publishing</category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ifanswers.com/813/questjs-asked-quest-file-save-quest-adventure-saves-aslx-file</guid>
<pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2015 01:01:51 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Is there a Javascript Interpreter for TADS that I can run on my website?</title>
<link>http://ifanswers.com/774/there-javascript-interpreter-for-tads-that-can-run-website</link>
<description>&lt;p&gt;I have a website, and I want people to be able to play my adventure from my webpage. Is there source code available for a javascript TADS that I could run on my website? I know IFDB has a &quot;play online&quot; web interpreter, but idk what it is / where it is / how I would use it with my website&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<category>Publishing</category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ifanswers.com/774/there-javascript-interpreter-for-tads-that-can-run-website</guid>
<pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2015 20:38:46 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Can you use custom CSS files with games uploaded to textadvenures.co.uk?</title>
<link>http://ifanswers.com/752/can-you-use-custom-files-with-games-uploaded-textadvenures</link>
<description>&lt;p&gt;I released an Inform 7 game along with the Quixe  interpreter and set up a custom CSS file for it in the Interpreter folder. On my computer the stylesheet works, but when I zip the release folder and upload it to  textadventures.co.uk, playing it online brings up the default stylesheet.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<category>Publishing</category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ifanswers.com/752/can-you-use-custom-files-with-games-uploaded-textadvenures</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2015 10:59:45 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>How should you attribute an extensions you've made a small change to?</title>
<link>http://ifanswers.com/640/how-should-you-attribute-extensions-youve-made-small-change</link>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Regarding the previous answer about modifying extensions (linked below):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What if you'd otherwise be able to follow steps one through four to handle most of the changes, but one small thing is preventing that? For instance, there's one inclusion that must be commented out in order for the extension to be compatible with something else, or there's a single bug in the original extension that prevents it from compiling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the only thing you change about the whole extension is a bug fix or inclusion,  it seems to me that attributing the modified version to a new author as in the example for number 5 above&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Version 2 of Greeter by Angela Author begins here.

&quot;Automatically greeting the player when the story begins.&quot;

&quot;based on the original extension by Random Q Hacker&quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;isn't quite fair to the original author, who did 99% of the work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I suppose it may be different if there are semi-substantial, non-bug-related changes in addition to that single bug or inclusion that requires direct editing? Or in that case would you just fix the extension directly, leave it attributed to the original author, and then make the other, bigger changes in one of the preferred ways (#1-4)?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Either way, I'm curious if the &quot;small edit&quot; aspect affects the example given previously (where, since the extension is modified directly, it has been copied to a new extension, modified, and attributed to the modifying author).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<category>Publishing</category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ifanswers.com/640/how-should-you-attribute-extensions-youve-made-small-change</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 22 May 2015 13:58:18 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Can I edit a game that I have already published?</title>
<link>http://ifanswers.com/599/can-i-edit-a-game-that-i-have-already-published</link>
<description>
</description>
<category>Publishing</category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ifanswers.com/599/can-i-edit-a-game-that-i-have-already-published</guid>
<pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2015 17:36:53 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>How do I delete a game?</title>
<link>http://ifanswers.com/505/how-do-i-delete-a-game</link>
<description>
</description>
<category>Publishing</category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ifanswers.com/505/how-do-i-delete-a-game</guid>
<pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2015 20:03:55 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Stupid Reviews on My Game!</title>
<link>http://ifanswers.com/485/stupid-reviews-on-my-game</link>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Hi there,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I made a text adventure on The Stanley Parable last year, and ever since,  I've been getting a few bad reviews from it simply because... get this... it wasn't the actual Stanley Parable game! Yes! Kids (I assume) come to my game thinking it is the real thing, and when they find it's not (big surprise), they give bad reviews and comments and usually vote it 0-2 stars! I am outraged that they think they can do this to me and it really hurts to see a game I worked on for so long is being bashed for really no reason at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is there any kind of response mechanism I can use to reply to these bastards? I can't just sit back and take this!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nintendex&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<category>Publishing</category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ifanswers.com/485/stupid-reviews-on-my-game</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2015 10:46:48 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Why is my game still &quot;unlisted&quot; on textadventures.co.uk?</title>
<link>http://ifanswers.com/444/why-is-my-game-still-unlisted-on-textadventures-co-uk</link>
<description>&lt;p&gt;I have a game on the Text Adventures called &quot;Wandering and Shrinking (1.0.1)&quot;, however I could never tell if it was ever actually uploaded.  Whenever I went to edit the game and make sure it was visible, it defaulted to &quot;unlisted&quot;.  I repeatedly set it to public, but I was never sure if it was really public.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I decided to try editing my profile, since I also have an issue where I do not have a profile picture like everyone else.  I made a new password, and suddenly when I went to check my games, the game had gone missing from my list!  It apparently had made a new profile for my new password (which is a load of malarkey) and I had to relog in with my Google account, since that was what I had used originally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of these issues have simply baffled me, and I am really interested in using this web service.  Can somebody explain to me what might be happening?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<category>Publishing</category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ifanswers.com/444/why-is-my-game-still-unlisted-on-textadventures-co-uk</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2015 23:30:59 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>